Bienen, Leigh B.; Papers apap312
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material, 1979-2011, Undated; 2; 7 cubic ft.
  - Death Penalty Abolition Polls, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 69)
  - Death Penalty Research Titles, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 70)
  - Death Sentences overturned on basis on fundamental justice amendment, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 71)
  - Death Penalty Stance of 2002 Attorney General Candidates, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 72)
  - Ethics and Post conviction Waivers, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 73)
  - Federal and Attorney General guidelines for selection of capital cases, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 74)
  - Federal Lethal Injection Challenges, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 75)
  - Federal and State Concurrent Jurisdiction, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 76)
  - Doug Finke, "Committee Oks call to abolish death penalty in Illinois, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 77)
  - Samuel R. Gross, "Still Unfair, Still Arbitrary - But do we Care?" Keynote Address, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 78)
  - Illinois Attorney Statute, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 79)
  - Illinois Litigation Trust Fund legislation, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 80)
  - Illinois Clemency Power, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 81)
  - Illinois Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Annual meeting invitation, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 82)
  - Illinois Compiled Statute section on the Illinois Capital Litigation Trust Fund, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 83)
  - Illinois Death Penalty Decision Guidelines and Qualifications, 2010; Undated (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 84)
  - Illinois Courts Chat, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 85)
  - Illinois Court of Claims - wrongful convictions, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 86)
  - Illinois Death Penalty Sentencing instructions 2008 update, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 87)
  - Illinois Death Penalty Sentencing instructions current to 2008, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 88)
  - Illinois House Bill 5687, abolition of the death penalty, 2010 (Box 6 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 89)
  - Illinois Legislation - Decertification of full-time and part-time police officers, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 1)
  - Illinois Legislative History of Death Penalty Reform with annotations, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 2)
  - Illinois Pattern Instructions, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 3)
  - Illinois Pattern Jury Instructions - Death Penalty Cases 2008 Update (cite), 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 4)
  - Illinois Seminars on Capital Cases, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 5)
  - Illinois Senate Bill 574 (1999), 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 6)
  - Illinois Senate Bill 3569 - Death Penalty Abolition, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 7)
  - Illinois State Budget - Department of Corrections, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 8)
  - Illinois State Comptroller Contact Us, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 9)
  - Illinois Supreme Court Justices and former positions as prosecutors and state's Attorneys, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 10)
  - Illinois Supreme Court Rules, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 11)
  - Illinois Supreme Court Rules - Seminars on Capital Cases, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 12)
  - Illinois Tax Foundation, "A guide to the Illinois Appropriations Process", 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 13)
  - Illinois v. Thompson (minutes), 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 14)
  - "Jackson County Board cuts public defender salary by $46,000" (cited), 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 15)
  - Lake County and Kane County data, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 16)
  - Legal foundation for Illinois Governor's clemency power, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 17)
  - Marcia Lehr - wrongful conviction, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 18)
  - Letter to Michael J.Z. Mannheimer from Roger L. Thomas concerning Pennsylvania House bill 1996, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 19)
  - List of Supreme Court cases that discuss not conducting Proportionality Review, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 20)
  - Material from Cecil E. Torres on Admissibility of mitigating evidence during a penalty phase trial, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 21)
  - Missouri Proportionality Review - Missouri v. Carman L. Deck, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 22)
  - "No Bail for Two Men Accused in Darien Murders", 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 23)
  - Nonstatutory Aggravating Factors, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 24)
  - NPR Coverage of Death Penalty costs in Illinois, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 25)
  - Notes - Illinois State's Attorneys salary cuts, ca. 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 26)
  - Notes on ineffective Assistance of Counsel, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 27)
  - Pew Report of Pension Obligations, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 28)
  - Sarah Pfander - Illinois Murders by County, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 29)
  - Prosecutors Statements, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 30)
  - Public Defender Representation - Weis v. Georgia, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 31)
  - Research credit, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 32)
  - Responsible Budget Coalition (FN 64), 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 33)
  - Reversals since 2003 reforms: Nelson, Lovejoy, Morris, Urdiales, Thompson, Mertz, and Albanese cases, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 34)
  - Small Illinois Counties and State's Attorneys and public defenders, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 35)
  - Sources on Blind lineups for footnote, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 36)
  - State Statutes - California, Washington, Utah, Illinois, Nebraska, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 37)
  - Supreme Court and "any evidence" at penalty phase, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 38)
  - Supreme Court of New Jersey 2000, Proportionality Review Project, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 39)
  - Bidish Sarma, et. al., "Struck by Lightning: Walker v. Georgia and Louisiana's Proportionality Review of Death Sentences" (cite), 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 40)
  - Christopher Michael Tansey, Appendix - Empirical Studies, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 41)
  - Christopher Tansey - Capital Litigation Trust Fund Expenditures, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 42)
  - Christopher Michael Tansey - Informal Bibliography, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 43)
  - Christopher Tansey Summary tables, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 44)
  - Michael P. Toomin, "Capital Punishment Reform and the Illinois Supreme Court: At the Forefront of change." (2004), 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 45)
  - Three Articles on Brian Dugan and DuPage County death penalty, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 46)
  - Typed notes on Burge and Brian Dugan costs, ca. 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 47)
  - U.S. Census Homicide Trends 1980 to 2005, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 48)
  - Utah Exoneration and Innocence Assistance Bill of 2008, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 49)
  - Neil Alan Weiner dedication, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 50)
  - Laura Weizeorick and Christopher Tansey, Summaries of Illinois Death Row Convictions since 2003, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 51)
  - Wrongful Conviction Compensation, 2010; Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 52)
  - Alex Yastrow, Radelet Study notes, time period of Cases, 2010 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 53)
  - Attorney's Letter to Governor Quinn Advocating for Abolition, 2011 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 54)
  - Illinois Death Penalty Literature, 2011 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 55)
  - Illinois House Bill 1519, 2011 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 56)
  - Illinois legislation to reinstate the death penalty, 2011 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 57)
  - Illinois Senate Bill 2276, 2011 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 58)
  - Senator Jeff Schoenberg and Governor Pat Quinn correspondence, 2011 (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 59)
  - Annotation of Capital Punishment Reform Provisions in Illinois, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 60)
  - Annotation of Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Provisions 1990- 1993, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 61)
  - Beck v. Alabama (1981) cite statistics, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 62)
  - Capital Jury Project - Juror Interview Instrument Phase II Part A, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 63)
  - Capital Jury Project - Juror Interview Instrument Phase II Part B, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 64)
  - Case Summaries, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 65)
  - Data Dictionary, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 66)
  - Homicide Data - Douglas Mills, Undated (Floppy-disk 2)
  - Illinois Senate Resolution on Ryan Moratorium, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 67)
  - January 1, 2004 Report of the Cook County State's Attorney's Office regarding monies received under Capital Crime Litigation Trust Fund Act, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 68)
  - Marcia Lehr - election of states attorneys in Illinois, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 69)
  - List of Aggravating Factors Associated with Illinois Death Row Inmates During Eligibility Phase, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 70)
  - Map of Illinois Counties, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 71)
  - Montana Cases (FN 135), Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 72)
  - "New chamber for execution ready to go into service" (Illinois), Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 73)
  - Note to John Murphy of the Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 74)
  - Prosecutorial discretion - case summaries, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 75)
  - Roots of Trial by Jury [class materials?], Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 76)
  - Slides: Implementing (or Nullifying) Atkins v. Virginia by John Blume, Sheri Johnson and Chris Seeds, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 77)
  - Table of Illinois Court of Claims cases, Undated (Box 7 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 78)
- Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Records, 2003-2010; 3; 0.8 cubic ft.
  Series contains records from Leigh Bienen's membership in the Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee. Material includes correspondence, meeting minutes, notes, and drafts and final copies of published reports.
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Act, 2003 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 1)
  - John Cullerton, Kirk Dilliard, and Peter G. Baroni, "Capital Punishment Reform in Illinois: A Model for the Nation", 2004 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 2)
  - Appointments, meetings, hearings, and Annual Reports, 2005 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 3)
  - Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Public Hearing - Springfield, 2006 November 13 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 4)
  - Peter G. Baroni, Special Counsel - Summary of Capital Cases Decided by the Illinois Supreme Court January 2003 to February 2007 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 5)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Material - Survey methods, data, meeting minutes, 2007 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 6)
  - Lobbying Entry Registration, 2007 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 7)
  - Public Hearing - Chicago, 2007 February 26 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 8)
  - Capital Crime Tables, 2008; 2009 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 9)
  - David E. Olson presentation slides with notes, ca. 2008 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 10)
  - David E. Olson, "Trends in the Number & Characteristic of Prison Sentences Imposed on Those Convicted of First Degree Murder in Illinois", (presented to the Illinois Capital Reform Study Committee), ca. 2008 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 11)
  - Slides of Graphs from meeting, 2008 January 28 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 12)
  - Act with Police Investigation Subcommittee, 2009; 2010 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 13)
  - Hearing of the Capital Reform Study Committee, 2009 March 2 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 14)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Fifth Annual Report, 2009 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 15)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2009 December 17 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 16)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Experiences with the Implementation of Homicide Investigative Reforms: A Survey of Illinois Local Law Enforcement Agencies", (Draft) Prepared for the Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee, 2009 July (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 17)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., Final Report - The Impact of Illinois' Truth-in-Sentencing Law on Sentence Lengths, Time to Serve and Disciplinary Incidents of Convicted Murderers and Sex Offenders, 2009 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 18)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Tables Summarizing the Sentencing of First Degree Murderers in Illinois" (Draft), 2009 March (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 19)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Tables Summarizing the Sentencing of First Degree Murderers in Illinois, State Fiscal Years 1989 through 2009", 2009 September (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 20)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Tables Summarizing the Sentencing of First Degree Murderers in Illinois, Determinate, Natural Life and Death Sentences Imposed State Fiscal Years 1989 through 2009" (FN 92), 2009 September (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 21)
  - Public Hearing Memo, 2009 March 2 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 22)
  - Public Hearing Notes, Sarah Pfouder [?], 2009 January 26 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 23)
  - Stenographic Report of Public Hearing, 2009 January 26 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 24)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee - Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 August 13 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 25)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee - Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 September 10 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 26)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee - Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 September 10 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 27)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 October 13 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 28)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Sixth and Final Report (included sealed CD), 2010 October 29 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 29)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Sixth and Final Report, [digital files on sealed CD], 2010 October 29 (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 30)
  - Kevin Lyons presentation material from March 2, 2010 public hearing (Box 1 (3-Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee), Folder 31)
- State Death Penalty Law Summaries, 1994-1996, Undated; 4; 0.4 cubic ft.
  Alphabetical by state
  Copies of many states' capital punishment legislation with summaries written by Northwestern University Law Librarian Marcia Lehr.
  - Notes describing series, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 1)
  - Alabama - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1995 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 2)
  - Arizona - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 3)
  - Arkansas - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 4)
  - California - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 5)
  - Colorado - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 6)
  - Connecticut - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 7)
  - Delaware - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 8)
  - Florida - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 9)
  - Georgia - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 10)
  - Idaho - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 11)
  - Illinois - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 12)
  - Indiana - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 13)
  - Kansas - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1994 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 14)
  - Kentucky - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 15)
  - Louisiana - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1995 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 16)
  - Maryland - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 17)
  - Mississippi - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1995 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 18)
  - Missouri - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 19)
  - Nebraska, New Hampshire, Nevada - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 20)
  - New Hampshire - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 21)
  - New Mexico - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 22)
  - New Mexico, North Carolina, Ohio - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1994 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 23)
  - New York - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 24)
  - Oklahoma, Oregon, South Carolina, South Dakota, Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 25)
  - Oregon - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 26)
  - Tennessee - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 27)
  - Tennessee, Utah, Virginia, Washington, Wyoming - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1 (4-State Death Penalty Law Summaries), Folder 28)
- Reference Materials, 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated; 5; 8.2 cubic ft.
  This series consists of the general research and reference file of Leigh Bienen. This includes publications, reports, and legislation on subjects such as capital punishment, criminal law, rape, and prison reform.
  - William Blackstone, "Commentaries on the Laws of England in Four Books" (photocopy), 1872 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Albert E. Arent and John W. Macdonald, "The Felony Murder Doctrine and it's Application under New York Statutes", 1935 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - Erwin L. Feiertag, "Capital Punishment in New Jersey: 1664-1950, a study of change", 1951 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - T. C. N. Gibbens, "Sane and Insane Homicide", 1959 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - N. M. Ollennu, "The Influence of English Law on West Africa", 1961 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Hugo A. Bedau, "Death Sentences in New Jersey", 1964 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 6)